HALED ALKHATIB

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

► khaledkhatib91@hotmail.com ♦ https://www.khaledalkhatib.com/ ♦ (416) 428 8759 ♦ Toronto, ON

in khaledalkhatib/ \(\Omega\) Khaled91Alkhatib

SUMMARY

A tenacious full stack/frontend web developer with a background in sales. Thinking of the results of a certain code and mentally using these results to problem solve another piece of the puzzle is what keeps me motivated and pushes me to want to learn more. I thrive on "theory crafting". Experience working in collaborative environments and timed projects.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Python, HTML5, SCSS, CSS3, Ruby

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES & ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, ReactJS, Express, JQuery, Ajax, Axios

DATABASES & SYSTEMS: PostgreSQL, Github TESTING LIBRARIES: Mocha, Chai, Jest

PROJECTS

Current **Footprints**

A virtual E-commerce website with enhanced UI/UX design for selling shoes.

Tech Stack: React, HTML, SASS, Axios and Stripe on the front-end and Node, Express, EJS and PostgresSQL on the back-end.

The Hardware Crew Apr. 2023

An E-Commerce website for selling computer peripherals.

The app is deployed using Railway and Netlify. To check the code and the readme, please visit

https://github.com/Khaled91Alkhatib/the-hardware-crew

Tech Stack: React, HTML, SASS, Axios and Stripe on the front-end and Node, Express, EJS and PostgresSQL on the back-end.

Oct. 2022 Video Zone

Youtube clone implemented using React and data fetched from RapidAPI.

Tech Stack: React, SASS.

EDUCATION

2022 **Lighthouse Labs**

Diploma in Full Stack Web Development.

Misr University for Science and Technology

Honours Bachelor's Degree of Oral and Dental Medicine / Surgery with Internship Certificate.

EMPLOYMENT

MyBranz, Frontend Web Developer Intern

Jan. 2024 - Current

2012 - 2017

- Set up the frontend side of MyBranz website using different APIs.
- Adjusting and modifying the styles to match the Figma design.

2023 - Current Freelancer, Web Developer

- Help clients by setting up their e-commerce websites using Shopify.
- Adjusting payments and delivery options based on clients' needs (pickup, shipping or delivery).
- Modifying Shopify themes to match clients' requests.

Damas Medical Company, Sales Representative, Jeddah, KSA

2017 - 2019

- Collaborate with team members to develop an invoice made up of non pharmaceutical products such as lotions, shampoos and beauty products to supply pharmacies in order to meet deadlines.
- Analyzed invoices on a continuous basis to ensure orders were correct with the aim of building trust and customer satisfaction with pharmacies.
- Responsible for conducting customer service communication with pharmacy's to answer questions, concerns, complaints and problems with their orders and come up with solutions that improves a customers experience.